thebulletin.org 2019-04-14

# Privacy Policy - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists

## Our Approach to Privacy

This policy describes the privacy practices of the _Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists_ (“ _Bulletin_ ”), [1307 E 60th St Chicago, IL 60637](https://www.google.com/maps/place/1307+E+60th+St,+Chicago,+IL+60637/@41.7856991,-87.5961256,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x880e2910b2e17125:0x6f37fe829c787c38!8m2!3d41.7856991!4d-87.5939369) (“us” “our” or “we”), for its website https://thebulletin.org (“Website”), including the mobile version of the Website. This policy does not apply to information we collect offline. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to set out how we collect, store, process, transfer, share and use your personal information. We collect and process data on users of our Website when they voluntarily submit information directly to us, and when they access and use this Website (these individuals about whom we collect data are referred to as “you” and “your” in this Privacy Policy).

##  **We collect information from and about you.**

 **We collect contact information.** We might collect your name and email address if you sign up for our e-newsletter on the Website. We may also collect your street address or phone number.  
**We collect payment information.** If you make a donation on the Website, we or our vendors collect credit card information from you, including name, credit card number and billing address, in order to process the donation.  
**We collect information you submit or post.** We collect the information you post in a public space on our Website. If you contact us, apply for a job, or respond to a survey, we will collect the information you provide to us.  
**We collect demographic information**. We may collect your gender and your zip code or postal code. We might also ask for information like your age.  
**We collect other information.** If you use our Website, we may collect information about the browser you are using. We might track the pages you visit. We might look at what site you came from, or what site you visit when you leave us. We collect this information using the tracking tools described here. To control those tools, please refer to the below section titled “Cookies and Similar Technologies.” We may also collect your GPS location if you use one of our mobile apps. We might look at how often you use the app and where you downloaded it.

## We collect information in different ways.

 **We collect information directly from you.** For example, if you sign up for our e-newsletter on the Website or make a donation.  
**We collect information from you passively**. We may use tracking tools like browser cookies or similar technology. We may collect information about users over time when you use this Website. We may have third parties collect personal information this way.  
**We combine information.** For example, we may combine information that we have collected offline with information we collect online. Or we may combine information we get from a third party with information we already have.

## Cookies and Similar Technologies.

The Website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Website and also allows us to improve the Website. “Cookies” are pieces of code that allow for personalization of our website experience by saving your information such as your preferences. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your device’s hard disk (such as your computer or smartphone) for record-keeping purposes. We may also collect “usage data,” which is information about how you view our Website (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click); information about your browser and usage patterns (e.g., your IP address, browser type and language); and information about the device you use to access the Online Services (e.g., device identifier, device type, model and manufacturer.  
We use tracking tools like browser cookies and web beacons to improve our products and your experience on the Website by collecting information about the browser you are using and how you use the Website. Some of the cookies we use are required to enable core site functionality, but we also use cookies that allow us to analyze site usage (so we can measure and improve performance. We may combine information collecting from our tracking tools with information we collect offline or receive from third parties to serve you interest-based or targeted advertisements such as ads about new products or special offers, including third party products and offers that we think you might find interesting.

The cookies we use are designed to help you get the most from the Website but if you do not wish to receive cookies, most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. Please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of our Website. These settings will typically be found in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the “Help” option in your browser for more details.

(a) Cookie settings in [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)  
(b) Cookie settings in [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/cookies-information-websites-store-on-your-computer?redirectlocale=en-US&redirectslug=Cookies)  
(c) Cookie settings in [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en)  
(d) Cookie settings in [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US) on Mac and Safari on [iPhone, iPad, or iPod touch](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201265).

##  **We use information as disclosed and described here.**

Your data is collected to allow us to provide our Services, as well as for the purposes described below:

 **We use information to respond to your requests or questions**. For example, we might use your information to send you our e-newsletter or to respond to you when you contact us.  
**We use your information for marketing purposes.** For example, we might send you information about content on our website that we believe may be interesting to you. We might also use your information to serve you ads about products or offers from us or third parties. We might tell you about new features or updates to our Website.  
**We use information to improve our Website.** We might use your information to customize your experience with us.  
**We use information to look at site trends and customer interests**. We may use your information to make website or product improvements. We may also combine information we get from you with information about you we have gotten from third parties.  
**We use information for security purposes.** We may use information to protect our company and our customers. **We also use information to protect our Website.**  
**We may use information to communicate with you**. For example, we will communicate with you about your subscription to the newsletter or your donation. We may also contact you about giving us feedback. We may also contact you to tell you about changes to this policy or our website Terms.  
**We use information as otherwise permitted by law or as we may notify you.** We will get your consent as required by law.

## We may store information both in and outside of the United States.

Your data is processed at our operating offices in the United States and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.  Depending on your location, data transfers may involve transferring of your Personal Data to a country other than your own. Any international transfers of your personal information are made pursuant to appropriate safeguards, such as standard data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission. If you wish to enquire further about these safeguards used, please contact us using the details set out at the end of this privacy policy.

If you live outside of the United States, you understand and agree that we may transfer your information to the United States as described herein.

You are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by us to safeguard your Data. If any such transfer takes place, you can find out more by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

## We retain Personal Data for a limited time.

We will store your Personal Data for no longer than necessary for the purpose for which it has been collected for and in accordance with our legal obligations.

We may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever you have given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, we may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.  Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

## We may share information with third parties.

 **We will share information with third parties who perform services on our behalf.** For example, we may share information with vendors who operate our Website, collect payment information to process donations, send the e-newsletter, provide us analytical data regarding Website usage, provide personalized advertising, collect web traffic data for third party content displayed on our Website, facilitate the ability to comment on our content, allow for interaction with third party social networks and platforms, manage our contacts list and allows us to send communications, We may authorize these vendors to collect information on our behalf and share certain information with their subcontractors, but only to the extent necessary for the vendors to perform services on our behalf. Our vendors may be located within or outside of North America. If you would like additional information about how our services providers use your information or who our service providers are, please contact us.  
**We will share information if we think we have to in order to comply with the law or to protect ourselves.** For example, we will share information to respond to a court order or subpoena. We may also share it if a government agency or investigatory body requests. We might share information when we are investigating potential fraud. We may share your information with the US government.  
**We may share information with the public and through social media.** When you use our Services, content and information that you post on message boards, blogs or other services on our Website, or that you allow us to make public, may be available to other visitors to our Website and to the general public. Also, content that you share through social media may be shared with your social media account provider and your friends, followers or contacts on the connected social network.  
**We will share information with any successor to all or part of our business**. For example, if part of our business was sold we may give our customer list as part of that transaction.  
**We will share information for other reasons we may describe to you.**

## Your Rights in Respect of Your Personal Information.

If you are resident in the EU/EEA, or if You are receiving services from, or otherwise engaging with the _Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists_ in the EU/EEA, under European law you have the following rights in respect of your personal information that we hold:

• **Right to withdraw your consent at any time.** You have the right to withdraw your consent where you have previously given your consent to the processing of your Personal Data.

• **Right to object to processing of Your Data**. You have a right to object to any processing based on our legitimate interests where there are grounds relating to your particular situation. There may be compelling reasons for continuing to process your personal information, and we will assess and inform you if that is the case. You must know that, however, should your Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, you can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification.

• **Right to access your Data.** You have the right to obtain: confirmation of whether, and where, we are processing your Personal Data; (ii) information about the categories of Personal Data we are processing, the purposes for which we process your Personal Data and information as to how we determine applicable retention periods; (iii) information about the categories of recipients with whom we may share your Personal Data; and (iv) a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you.

• **Right of portability.** You have the right, in certain circumstances, to receive a copy of the Personal Data you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format that supports re-use, or to request the transfer of your Personal Data to another person.

• **Right to verify and seek rectification.** You have the right to verify the accuracy of your Personal Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.

• **Right to restrict the processing of your Data.** You have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of your Personal Data if the continued processing of your data in this way is not justified, such as where the accuracy of the personal information is contested by you. In this case, we will not process your Personal Data for any purpose other than storing it.

• **Right to have your Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** You have the right, under certain circumstances, to have us erase your Personal Data without undue delay if the continued processing of that data is not justified.

• **Right to lodge a complaint.** You have the right to bring a claim before your competent data protection authority. Further information about how to contact your local data protection authority is available at <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>.

For more information on your rights, please see <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/reform/rights-citizens_en>.

If you wish to exercise one of these rights, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Any request to exercise a right mentioned herein can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by us as early as possible.

##  **Additional information about our collection and processing of Personal Data**

 **Legal action  
**Your Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by us in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Website or the related Services. You declare to be aware that we may be required to reveal your Personal Data upon request of public authorities.  
**Additional information about your Personal Data**  
In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Website may provide you with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.  
**System logs and maintenance**  
For operation and maintenance purposes, this Website and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Website (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

## Our policy towards children

Our Services are not directed at persons under 16 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under 16. If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information, without your consent, then please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) so that we can take steps to remove such information and terminate any account your child has created with us.

## Your California Privacy Rights

If you reside in California, you have the right to ask us one time each year if we have shared personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make a request, please contact us by email using “Privacy Policy/Ad and Cookie Policy” as the subject of your message, and indicate in your message that you are a California resident making a “Shine the Light” inquiry.

## Information not contained in this policy

This website may contain links to other sites. Please be aware the _Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists_ is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement policy applies solely to information collected by this website.

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from us at any time at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

##  **How “Do Not Track” requests are handled**

This Website does not support “Do Not Track” requests. To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read Your privacy policies.

## SECURITY:

We use standard security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the data we collect. Still, because there are risks on the Internet, we cannot promise that your use of our sites will be completely safe. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. This includes not sharing your passwords.

## Owner and Data Controller

When you visit this Website, we are responsible for your Personal Data that you have provided to us or that we have collected from you. In these instances, we will act as the data controller in respect of your Personal Data. We can be reached at: _Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists_ , [1307 E 60th St Chicago, IL 60637](https://www.google.com/maps/place/1307+E+60th+St,+Chicago,+IL+60637/@41.7856991,-87.5961256,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x880e2910b2e17125:0x6f37fe829c787c38!8m2!3d41.7856991!4d-87.5939369); by mail at: PO Box 15461, Chicago, IL 60615-5146; or by email at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

## We may update this policy.

From time to time we may change our privacy policies. We will provide notice of any material changes to our Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website. Please check our site periodically for updates.
